Matt Forster

Student - BSc Computer Science

forster.matth@gmail.com

Summary

Second year Computer Science Student, Lifeguard.

Goals: Software Engineer, Programmer, Developer.

Creating awesome things, solving problems and maintaining good code keeps me happy and motivated. I am interested in web development, application development, and other projects that allow me to create and help people.

I've dreamed of working for NASA, and I've made it a goal in my life to help the human race move forward in some significant way.

I am looking forward to my Computer Science schooling at the University of Lethbridge, and my career in technology in the future.

Honors and Awards

Honorable Mention - ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest

Association for Computing Machinery

October 2012

Competed in the ACM-ICPC at the University of Alberta on behalf of Lethbridge College.

In a team with two of my classmates, we solved programming problems under a time constraint in a competitive environment.

College Honors

Lethbridge College

December 2011

Awarded for achieving GPA over 3.7

College Honors

Lethbridge College

April 2012

Awarded for achieving GPA over 3.7

College Honors

Lethbridge College

December 2012

Awarded for achieving GPA over 3.7

Jason Lang Scholarship

Alberta Government

December 2012

Awarded for Academic Excellence

Projects

Lab Information Indexing System - Lethbridge Research Center

September 2012 to April 2013

Members: Matt Forster, David Sinclaire, Andrew Sanders, Graham Fluet

Project Lead

Creating a storage database, with a web driven user interface for a lab at the Lethbridge Research Center. The CRUD database will hold culture and sample information on a server that scientists and technicians can access from anywhere within the facility.

Skills used during this project:

Apache, MySQL, HTML/CSS, JavaScript (jQuery), and PHP.

Education

The University of Lethbridge

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Computer Science, 2013 - 2016

Lethbridge College

Computer Information Technology, Computer Science, 2011 - 2013

Grade: Honors

Activities and Societies: ACM International Collegiate Programming Team

Skills & Expertise

 \mathbf{C}

C++

CSS

HTML

Computer Hardware

Teaching

Java

PHP

MySQL

Apache

JavaScript

Oracle

Windows Server

Management of small teams Programming

Volunteer Experience

Swim Coach at Special Olympics Canada

January 2009 - January 2011 (2 years 1 month)

Swim Coach at Lethbridge Special Olympics, traveled to swim meets and helped support athletes.

Experience

Tutor at Lethbridge College

September 2012 - Present (8 months)

Student Tutor, helping classmates gain excellence and achieve goals.

Tutoring Programming and Database Theory.

Student at Lethbridge College

September 2011 - Present (1 year 8 months)

Computer Information Technology, Second Year.

Aquatic Leader at Recreation Excellence

March 2008 - Present (5 years 2 months)

Shift manager. Leader of 3 or more lifeguards.

Interests

Mountain Biking, Swimming, Hiking, Backpacking.

Matt Forster

Student - BSc Computer Science

forster.matth@gmail.com



Contact Matt on LinkedIn